Delaware Street Baptist Church Records
Delaware Street Baptist Church Records
1928-1965
Delaware Street Baptist Church.
0.25 linear ft.
Minutes and records of the Syracuse, New York church.
3164198
Biographical History
The Delaware Street Baptist Church in Syracuse, New York, was founded in 1889 and housed in a large brick building on the corner of Dudley and Delaware streets. At its height it had several hundred members, and was one of three west-side churches (the other two were Brown Memorial United Methodist and St. Paul's Lutheran Church) that collaborated to form West Side Ministries. In the mid-2000s the congregation moved to Fay Road in Westvale, and is today known as the Fay Road Baptist Church. [Taken in part from "THE DELAWARE ST. BAPTIST CHURCH".
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Delaware Street Baptist Church Records consists of minutes and other records of a New York church.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence and meeting minutes are arranged chronologically. Subject files are arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; New York State; Delaware Street Baptist Church.; Baptist Church -- New York (State) -- History.; Syracuse (New York) -- History.; Church records.; Correspondence.; Minutes (administrative records)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Unspecified, circa 1965.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - General, 1939; 1959,; 1962-1964 (Box 1)
- Meetings
  - Donor notes, 1964 or 1965 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1928-1930; 1932,; 1938,; 1941-1947,; 1949-1965; 11 folders (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Clippings, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Fire and reconstruction costs, 1958 (Box 1)
  - History and chronology, 1964 or 1965; covers 1889 to 1964 (Box 1)
  - Index of events mentioned in minutes (Box 1)
  - Pageant, 60th anniversary, 1949 (Box 1)